Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're bringing you part 9 of our romantic drama suspense action series, I'm
今天我们带来浪漫悬疑动作剧系列的第九部分，我
Sorry I Love You.
《对不起，我爱你》。
This is actually our penultimate lesson.
这其实是我们的倒数第二课。
Exactly, this story will end in part 10, so we're almost done.
没错，这个故事将在第十部分结束，所以我们快讲完了。
What's happening?
发生了什么？
Well, I am pretty excited to find out, so why don't we go straight into the dialogue
嗯，我很期待知道结果，所以我们直接进入对话
and catch up with Steven and Veronica.
看看Steven和Veronica怎么样了。
Veronica, wait.
Veronica，等等。
Come on, honey, get back in the car.
拜托，亲爱的，回车上来。
Let's talk it over, okay?
我们好好谈谈，好吗？
No, I'm tired of your lies.
不，我受够了你的谎言。
I don't know who you are anymore.
我已经不知道你是谁了。
Veronica, it's me, the man that has and always will love you.
Veronica，是我，那个一直爱着你、永远爱你的男人。
I'm sorry that I've lied to you, believe me.
对不起我骗了你，请相信我。
It's been hard for me as well.
这对我也很难。
And time and again, I've thought of coming clean.
我一次又一次想过坦白。
But I couldn't put you or my mission at risk.
但我不能让你或我的任务陷入危险。
It's all over now.
现在一切都结束了。
My assignment is complete.
我的任务完成了。
And now I have to go back to India.
现在我必须回印度了。
What?
什么？
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
Is there anything else I should know before I never see you again?
在我再也见不到你之前，还有什么我应该知道的吗？
How could you deceive me like that?
你怎么能这样欺骗我？
Yes.
是的。
Veronica, I know that this isn't the best time and you probably hate me right now, but
Veronica，我知道现在不是好时机，你可能恨我，但
I want to be completely forthright with you.
我想对你完全坦诚。
I know deep in my heart that you are the best thing that has ever happened to me.
我内心深处知道，你是我生命中最美好的事情。
Veronica, will you marry me?
Veronica，你愿意嫁给我吗？
Come with me to India, baby.
跟我去印度吧，宝贝。
I can't make it for everything that's happened, but I can promise you my undying love.
我无法弥补过去的一切，但我能承诺你永恒的爱。
I will be the most devoted husband and I will cherish you always.
我会是最忠诚的丈夫，永远珍惜你。
Steven, I can't just leave everything at the drop of a hat.
Steven，我不能说走就走。
With everything that has happened between us, I just don't know you anymore.
经历了我们之间的一切，我真的不了解你了。
I just can't build a relationship on a foundation of lies.
我无法在谎言的基础上建立关系。
I do love you, but I can't go with you.
我确实爱你，但我不能跟你走。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I love you.
我爱你。
This is the last call for flight A15 from Los Angeles to Hyderabad.
这是从洛杉矶飞往海德拉巴的A15航班的最后一次登机广播。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
We can't wait any longer.
我们不能再等了。
You must board the plane.
您必须登机了。
Are you waiting for someone?
您在等人吗？
I was, but I don't think she's coming.
我在等，但我觉得她不会来了。
All right, so it seems like our poor Steven is going home by himself.
好吧，看来我们可怜的史蒂文要一个人回家了。
It's so sad.
真让人难过。
I know.
我知道。
She proposed, she didn't accept, and now he's going back to India by himself.
他求婚了，她没接受，现在他要一个人回印度了。
I think this must be one of the worst feelings in the world, wondering if the person you
我觉得这一定是世界上最糟糕的感觉之一，想知道你爱的人
love is going to show up at the last minute and realizing they aren't.
会不会在最后一刻出现，却发现他们不会来。
I think it's very common of movies, you always expect the person to come running and show
我觉得这在电影里很常见，你总是期待那个人会跑着出现，
up, but as you can see, our dialogues are more realistic, so it didn't happen in this
但你看，我们的对话更现实，所以这次没发生。
occasion.
更现实。
More realistic.
Okay.
好吧。
Anyway, let's not debate that topic.
总之，我们别争论这个话题了。
Let's go straight into the language now with Language Takeaway.
我们直接进入今天的语言学习环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言学习环节。
All right, so today on Language Takeaway, we have six words that we're going to be looking
好的，今天在语言学习环节，我们要看六个单词，
at and let's get started with the first one.
让我们从第一个开始。
Okay, so we've got language about love and language about telling the truth.
好的，我们有关于爱情的语言和关于说实话的语言。
And the first one is a word about telling the truth.
第一个是关于说实话的词。
So Steven said, I've thought of coming clean.
所以史蒂文说，我曾想过坦白。
Okay, to come clean.
好的，坦白。
To come clean.
坦白。
Now if I want to come clean, it means I want to...
如果我想坦白，意思是我想要……
You want to admit to something or to tell the truth about something you've been hiding.
你想要承认某事，或者对你一直隐瞒的事情说实话。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so I want to finally tell the truth or confess.
好的，所以我想最终说出真相或承认。
So someone needs to come clean about who stole the chocolate out of the kitchen.
所以有人需要坦白是谁从厨房偷了巧克力。
Okay, come clean.
好的，坦白。
So Steven wanted to come clean on many occasions, but Veronica said, how could you deceive me
所以史蒂文在很多场合都想坦白，但维罗妮卡说，你怎么能那样欺骗我？
like that?
欺骗某人。
Deceive someone.
How could you deceive me?
你怎么能欺骗我？
So to deceive someone.
所以是欺骗某人。
All right, to deceive.
好的，欺骗。
When you deceive somebody, you make them believe something that is untrue.
当你欺骗某人时，你让他们相信不真实的事情。
So you kind of trick them.
所以你有点在耍他们。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
Okay, make them believe or see something that is not really true.
好，让他们相信或看到不真实的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, so that's the verb, to deceive.
好了，所以这是动词，欺骗。
Now the noun, the action of doing this is called deception.
现在名词，做这件事的行为叫做欺骗。
It was all a great deception.
这完全是一场大骗局。
Okay, so a big trick, something, a big untruth.
好，所以一个大骗局，一个不真实的东西。
You deceived me.
你骗了我。
All right, very good.
好了，非常好。
And now the opposite of deceive.
现在欺骗的反义词。
Is to be forthright.
是坦率。
Forthright.
坦率。
So Steven wants to be completely forthright with Veronica.
所以史蒂文想对维罗妮卡完全坦率。
Okay, I want to be forthright with you.
好，我想对你坦率。
All right, when you are forthright with somebody, you are very honest and truthful with them,
好，当你对某人坦率时，你对他们非常诚实和真实，
right?
对吧？
Direct.
直接。
You don't defend everything directly.
你不会直接回避一切。
So you don't hide it or soften it or anything.
所以你不会隐瞒或软化或任何东西。
Very good.
非常好。
So forthright.
所以坦率。
All right, so three words about honesty.
好了，所以关于诚实的三个词。
Now we've got three words about love for you.
现在我们为你准备了关于爱的三个词。
So Steven promised Veronica his undying love.
所以史蒂文向维罗妮卡承诺了他永恒的爱。
My undying love.
我永恒的爱。
Now undying.
现在永恒。
Well, I think it's pretty easy, right?
嗯，我觉得这很简单，对吧？
It won't die.
它不会死。
It won't die, exactly.
它不会死，没错。
So he's offering her his love forever.
所以他向她献上他永远的爱。
A very romantic phrase.
一个非常浪漫的短语。
Very romantic.
非常浪漫。
And he also promised to be a devoted husband.
他还承诺要做一个忠诚的丈夫。
Devoted husband.
忠诚的丈夫。
I'll be the most devoted husband.
我会是最忠诚的丈夫。
Now this word devoted, what am I saying there?
现在这个词“忠诚”，我在说什么？
So as a devoted husband, Steven really, really would love his wife.
所以作为一个忠诚的丈夫，史蒂文真的、真的会爱他的妻子。
He'd really look after her well and he would put all of his energy into his marriage, right?
他真的会好好照顾她，把全部精力都投入到婚姻中，对吧？
Okay, so he would be very committed to her.
好的，所以他会对她非常忠诚。
And work really hard.
而且会非常努力。
Now can I change the noun husband for something else?
现在我能把“丈夫”这个名词换成别的吗？
Yeah, we can talk about a devoted friend.
可以，我们可以说一个忠诚的朋友。
Or a devoted father.
或者一个忠诚的父亲。
Or a devoted employee.
或者一个忠诚的员工。
Very good.
非常好。
And our last word about love.
还有我们关于爱情的最后一个词。
Well, Steven also promises to cherish Veronica.
嗯，史蒂文也承诺要珍惜维罗妮卡。
Okay, I will cherish you always.
好的，我会永远珍惜你。
I will cherish you always.
我会永远珍惜你。
So if I cherish somebody like my girlfriend, what would that mean?
所以如果我珍惜某人，比如我的女朋友，那意味着什么？
That means you hold her in your heart, like you really love her and you really respect
那意味着你把她放在心里，就像你真的很爱她、很尊重
her and you hold her close in your heart.
她，并且把她紧紧放在心里。
Okay, so I respect her and maybe you don't take that person for granted.
好的，所以我尊重她，也许你不会把那个人视为理所当然。
To cherish someone.
珍惜某人。
Yeah.
嗯。
Alright, so some nice honesty words, some nice love words and I think now we can move
好了，所以有一些很好的诚实词汇，一些很好的爱情词汇，我想现在我们可以
on to some interesting phrases with Fluency Builder.
进入流畅表达部分的一些有趣短语了。
Fluency Builder.
流畅表达。
Alright, so Veronica was upset.
好的，所以维罗妮卡很沮丧。
She didn't want to get back in the car and Steven said, let's talk it over, okay?
她不想再回到车里，史蒂文说，我们好好谈谈，好吗？
Let's talk it over.
我们好好谈谈。
To talk something over.
好好谈谈某事。
Now if I tell you that I want to talk it over, what am I saying?
如果我告诉你我想好好谈谈，我在说什么？
Well obviously you want to talk about it, right?
嗯，显然你想谈论这件事，对吧？
But you want to talk about it for some time.
但你想花些时间谈论它。
To really talk about all of the problems and the issues and everything.
真正地讨论所有的问题和事情。
So to try and make things clear.
所以是为了把事情弄清楚。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright.
好的。
So when he was confessing, he said, time and again I've thought of coming clean.
所以当他坦白时，他说，一次又一次我想过坦白。
So this phrase, time and again.
所以这个短语，一次又一次。
Time and again.
一次又一次。
So that's basically the same as saying again and again or many times.
所以这基本上和“再三”或“多次”一样。
Right.
对。
So time and again I've thought of quitting smoking but never really have done it.
所以一次又一次我想过戒烟，但从来没有真正做到过。
So you've thought many times of doing it.
所以你多次想过要这么做。
Time and again.
一次又一次。
Yep.
是的。
Alright, so let's go to our next phrase.
好了，那我们来看下一个短语。
Now Veronica said, I can't just leave everything at the drop of a hat.
维罗妮卡说：我不能说走就走。
At the drop of a hat.
说走就走。
So this is a very interesting and colloquial way of saying immediately.
这是一个非常有趣且口语化的表达方式，意思是“立刻”。
So why don't we hear a few examples of how this is used in English.
我们来听几个例子，看看它在英语中怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
My boss expects me to come into work at the drop of a hat.
我老板指望我随叫随到去上班。
Example two.
例子二。
Laura is always willing to help me at the drop of a hat.
劳拉总是愿意随时帮我。
Example three.
例子三。
I can't leave at the drop of a hat.
我不能说走就走。
I need time to prepare.
我需要时间准备。
Okay, so as you can see, you can change it for different things but basically you're
好的，如你所见，你可以根据不同的情况调整它，但基本上
saying I can't do something immediately.
是在说“我不能立刻做某事”。
Yeah, and it is almost always attached to this idea of doing something or going somewhere,
是的，而且它几乎总是和“做某事”或“去某地”、“在某地”这些概念联系在一起。
being somewhere.
对。
Very good.
非常好。
At the drop of a hat.
说走就走。
Alright, now our final phrase here for this lesson.
好了，现在是我们这节课的最后一个短语。
So Veronica was saying I can't go to India at the drop of a hat and she also said I just
维罗妮卡说：我不能说走就走地去印度，她还说：我无法
can't build a relationship on a foundation of lies.
在谎言的基础上建立一段关系。
Okay, a foundation of lies.
好的，谎言的基础。
To build something on a foundation of lies.
在谎言的基础上建立某物。
Now this is interesting.
这很有意思。
Let's take a look at this.
我们来看看这个。
Foundation what is that?
基础是什么？
Well you know you have a house, right?
你知道房子吧？
And the part that's in the ground that supports the house is the foundation.
埋在地里支撑房子的部分就是地基。
Okay, so it supports the entire structure.
好的，所以它支撑着整个结构。
Right.
对。
So here she refers to the lies as the foundation.
所以这里她把谎言比作地基。
And that's no way to start a strong relationship, is it?
这可不是建立牢固关系的方式，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So we use it metaphorically in this way but we can always, but we always have to say it,
所以我们用这个比喻的方式，但我们必须总是说它，
but we always have to use the verb build.
但我们必须总是用动词“建立”。
Okay, so it's basically to make something on a base of something else, right?
好的，所以基本上就是在某物的基础上建立另一物，对吧？
So for example, a strong relationship is built on a foundation of trust.
比如，一段牢固的关系是建立在信任的基础上的。
Or this country was built on a foundation of liberty.
或者说，这个国家是建立在自由的基础上的。
Very good.
很好。
So always use foundation with built.
所以，总是把 foundation 和 built 搭配使用。
Very good.
很好。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
And well I think we should listen to this dialogue for the last time and then we'll
嗯，我觉得我们应该再听一遍这段对话，然后
come back and talk a little bit more about Veronica and Steven.
回来再聊聊维罗妮卡和史蒂文的事。
Veronica, wait.
维罗妮卡，等等。
Come on, honey.
来吧，亲爱的。
Get back in the car.
回到车里去。
Let's talk it over, okay?
我们好好谈谈，好吗？
No.
不。
I'm tired of your lies.
我受够了你的谎言。
I don't know who you are anymore.
我已经不认识你了。
Veronica, it's me, the man that has and always will love you.
维罗妮卡，是我，那个一直爱着你、永远爱你的男人。
I'm sorry that I've lied to you, believe me.
对不起，我对你撒了谎，请相信我。
It's been hard for me as well and time and again I've thought of coming clean.
对我来说也很难，我一次又一次地想坦白。
But I couldn't put you or my mission at risk.
但我不能让你和我的任务陷入危险。
It's all over now.
现在一切都结束了。
My assignment is complete and now I have to go back to India.
我的任务完成了，现在我必须回印度了。
What?
什么？
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
Is there anything else I should know before I never see you again?
在我再也见不到你之前，还有什么我应该知道的吗？
How could you deceive me like that?
你怎么能这样欺骗我？
Yes.
是的。
Veronica, I know that this isn't the best time and you probably hate me right now but
维罗妮卡，我知道现在不是时候，你现在可能恨我，但
I want to be completely forthright with you.
我想对你完全坦诚。
I know deep in my heart that you are the best thing that has ever happened to me.
我内心深处知道，你是我生命中最美好的事情。
Veronica, will you marry me?
维罗妮卡，你愿意嫁给我吗？
Come with me to India, baby.
跟我去印度吧，宝贝。
I can't make it for everything that's happened but I can promise you my undying love.
我无法弥补过去的一切，但我可以向你保证我永恒的爱。
I will be the most devoted husband and I will cherish you always.
我会成为最忠诚的丈夫，永远珍惜你。
Stephen, I can't just leave everything at the drop of a hat.
史蒂文，我不能说走就走。
With everything that has happened between us, I just don't know you anymore.
我们之间发生了这么多事，我已经不认识你了。
I just can't build a relationship on a foundation of lies.
我无法在谎言的基础上建立一段关系。
I do love you but I can't go with you.
我确实爱你，但我不能跟你走。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I love you.
我爱你。
This is the last call for flight A15 from Los Angeles to Hyderabad.
这是从洛杉矶飞往海得拉巴的A15航班最后一次登机广播。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
We can't wait any longer.
我们不能再等了。
You must board the plane.
您必须登机了。
Are you waiting for someone?
您在等人吗？
I was but I don't think she's coming.
我在等，但我觉得她不会来了。
So Marco, I think I see a bit of a tear there in the corner of your eye.
所以马可，我觉得我看到你眼角有点泪光。
I'm very sad.
我很难过。
I can't believe he proposed and she just said no.
我不敢相信他求婚了，她却拒绝了。
Just like that.
就这样拒绝了。
Well, it's not supposed to happen.
嗯，这不应该发生啊。
Plus, he was inviting her to India and exotic getaway and promising.
而且，他还邀请她去印度，一个异国风情的度假地，还承诺
Exotic getaway for the rest of her life.
给她一辈子的异国风情生活。
Well, what do you think will happen?
嗯，你觉得会发生什么？
Part 10, it all ends.
第10部分，一切都结束了。
So do you think they all just keep on living their separate lives?
所以你觉得他们都会继续各自的生活吗？
Will they meet again?
他们会再见面吗？
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
Come to our website and tell us what you think will happen.
来我们的网站告诉我们你认为会发生什么。
So you can find us at EnglishPod.com.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
All right.
好了。
Don't miss our finale of this lesson and until next time, we'll see you guys there.
不要错过我们这节课的大结局，下次再见，我们会在那里等你们。